## Kautzar Alibani

Email : <u>kalibani.ka@gmail.com</u> Phone/Whatsapp/Telegram : (+62) 87822946362

Linkedin : <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kautzar-alibani-04954613b/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/kautzar-alibani-04954613b/</a>

Github : <a href="https://github.com/kalibani">https://github.com/kalibani</a>
Portfolio : <a href="https://www.kautzaralibani.com/">https://www.kautzaralibani.com/</a>

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Hello, my name is Kautzar. I am currently a Lead Frontend Developer at a fintech company based in Indonesia, with six years of experience in frontend software engineering. I hold a BS degree in Computer Science and have completed a six-month intensive programming bootcamp, which provided me with a comprehensive understanding of my capabilities as a programmer. My expertise includes React.js, Next.js, Redux, React Native, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Vuex, Al-based applications, and Node.js. I have experience in both web and mobile hybrid development. I am a dedicated programmer who loves to learn, explore, and implement new technologies. Additionally, I excel in communication with both team members and stakeholders.

### **FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE**

- Javascript / Typescript / Html & Css/Scss/Tailwind/Styled component
- React / Next js / React Native -Redux
- Vue / Nuxt js Vuex / Pinia
- OPEN AI API
- Web 3 methodologies (Ethers.js, Third Web SDK, Solidity)

- Node.is & Express
- Git / Github / Bitbucket / Gitlab
- CI/CD Using Gitlab Pipeline and AWS S3
- PWA (Progressive Web App)
- Realtime engine socket.io / Firebase
- Deployment Google Cloud Platform, AWS S3, Heroku, Netlify

# **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

**Brick's Products** 

Role : Lead Frontend Developer

Language : React - Redux - Style component Project Description : Fintech Apps (Payment, KYB)

Release : https://www.onebrick.io/, https://app.onebrick.io/signin,

https://demo.onebrick.io/, https://www.boiva.id/,

**Achievement**: Winning a hackathon that help to solved one of company

problem by leveraging AI Tech

HireFazz - Al Saas Platform

Role : Full Stack Developer - Solo project

Language : Next JS, Typescript Tailwind, OpenAl API, Prisma, Stripe

**Project Description**: Full-stack Developer · A Saas AI Platform built using Next.js,

TypeScript, OpenAI, Langchain, Pinecone Vector Database, Prisma and Stripe provide a platform for helping recruiter

hired their best people effortlessly

Release : https://hirefazz.com

Repo : https://github.com/kalibani/HireFazz

Crowdfunding Platform - Web 3 Smart Contract Implementation
Role : Full Stack Developer - Solo project
Language : React JS, Solidity, Thirdweb, Hardhat

**Project Description**: Web 3 Smart Contract Implementation on top of ethereum

sepolia test network

Release : Crowdfunding Platform

Repo : Crowdfunding Github Repositories

OpenSea Clone - NFTs marketplace clone application

Role : Solo project

Language : Next js, Web 3.0 Methodologies, thirdweb, Metamask

**Project Description** : OpenSea clone blockchain Application

Release : <a href="https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/">https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/</a>
<a href="https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/">https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/</a>
<a href="https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/">https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/</a>

**Atlan Modern Data Workspace** 

**Role** : Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : Vue 3, Pinia, Vite

**Project Description**: Building a home for data teams

Release : <a href="https://atlan.com/">https://atlan.com/</a>

PermataNet E-Banking

**Role** : Lead Frontend Engineer

Language : React-Redux

Project Description : Revamp E-Banking Permata Bank Release : https://www.permatanet.com/pnet/

**Modal Rakyat P2P Platform** 

**Role** : Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : Node JS (Express) - Javascript (React-Redux)

**Project Description**: Building and maintaining peer to peer lending web

application using Node is as backend services, Docker

as it's containers and React as a UI javascript library

Release : <a href="https://www.modalrakyat.id/">https://www.modalrakyat.id/</a>

**Modal Rakyat Back Office CMS Platform** 

**Role** : Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : Node JS (Express) - Javascript (Vue JS)

**Project Description** : Building admin platform for handling back office process

Release : <a href="https://bo.modalrakyat.id">https://bo.modalrakyat.id</a>

Simple PWA

**Role** : Frontend Engineer

**Language** : React js

**Project description** : Simple Progressive Movie List Web App built in react js

Release: https://whispering-castle-94998.herokuapp.com

FindWork Web-App

**Role** : Frontend Engineer

Language : PHP (Laravel) - Javascript (Vue JS)

**Project Description**: Implementing design web-app based on UI/UX designer using

bootstrap and vue is

Release : https://www.findwork.io/

**Ecommerce** 

Role : Solo Project
Language : Javascript

**Project description**: Develop Simple Ecommerce website,

The server side (REST API) was built with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB. At the front side, I am use VueJs altogether with

Semantic UI

Source-Code : <a href="https://github.com/kalibani/ecommerce">https://github.com/kalibani/ecommerce</a>
Release : <a href="http://ecommerce.kautzaralibani.com">http://ecommerce.kautzaralibani.com</a>

To-do Fancy

Role : Solo Project

**Project Description** : A fancy to-do list application

Language : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : NodeJs, ExpressJs, VueJs, MongoDB BootstrapCSS

Source-Code : https://github.com/kalibani/todo-fancy-client &

https://github.com/kalibani/Todo-Fancy-server

**Release** : <a href="http://todofancy.kautzaralibani.com">http://todofancy.kautzaralibani.com</a>

**Hacktiv-OverFlow** 

A Mini Version of Stack Overflow Apps

Role : Solo project

Language : Javascript

**Project description**: Question-Answer Platform App

Frameworks and Libraries : Node Js, Express Js, Vue Js, MongoDB Bootstrap CSS

Source-Code : <a href="https://github.com/kalibani/HacktivOverflow">https://github.com/kalibani/HacktivOverflow</a>

https://github.com/kalibani/HacktivOverFlow-API

Release : <a href="http://hacktivoverflow.kautzaralibani.com/">http://hacktivoverflow.kautzaralibani.com/</a>

### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp (Full-Stack Web Development) Hacktiv8 (Jakarta, Indonesia) 2017 BS (Computer Science) Indonesian Computer University, (Bandung, Indonesia) Feb, 2016

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Company : Brick Technology Indonesia June 2022 – present (Indonesia)

Position : Lead Frontend Engineer

As a Tech Lead Frontend Engineer I am responsible for leading the team, managing resources, mentoring, driving the frontend stack and tech and also reviewing and maintaining the code.

- Leading and managing a team of frontend engineers to deliver winning products.
- Driving release and sprint planning sessions.
- Won a Hackathon that help solve company Problem by leveraging AI Tech.
- Determining frontend stack and tech.
- Design architecture of client side Application.
- Implementation of backend services.
- Review and maintain code.
- Collaborate and communicate with other teams and stakeholders about best practice of software development.

Company : Infosys Apr 2020 – May 2022 (Indonesia)

Position : Lead Frontend Engineer

As a Tech Lead Frontend Engineer i am responsible to manage the team, mentoring the junior, determine stack and tech, review and maintain code.

- Leading and managing a team of frontend engineers to deliver winning products.
- Driving release and sprint planning sessions.
- Get involved in determining stack and tech.
- Design architecture of client side Application.
- Design and implementation of backend services.
- Review and maintain code.
- Collaborate and communicate with other teams and stakeholders about best practice of software development.

Company : Atlan Jun 2019 – May 2020 (India)

Position : Senior Frontend Engineer

Atlan is an international modern data workspace company with a diverse team and environment. As a Senior Frontend Engineer i am responsible to build the feature, manage source code, maintain structure of the app, review and maintain code.

- Built a rich features App
- Create a pixel perfect component and UI based on figma design.
- Complete ownership of the module & feature.
- Code, test, ship & iterate.
- Review and maintain source code.
- communicate and Collaborate with other team members to deliver winning products.

Company : PT Modal Rakyat Indonesia Apr 2018 – Mei 2019 (Indonesia)

Position : Senior Frontend Engineer

As a Frontend Engineer, i responsible to deliver design UI and it's functionality

- Writing readable, maintainable and reusable code.
- Implementing design from sketch zeplin to real design using Html/Scss (Slicing)
- Build a feature and it's functionality using React Redux (main p2p web app) & Vue Js Framework (back office cms)
- Collaborate and communicate with other teams about best practices of software developers.

Company : PT Paket Indonesia Digital Apr 2017 – Apr 2018 (Indonesia)

Position : Frontend Engineer

As a Frontend Engineer i am responsible to build the feature, manage source code, make a decision about stack and tech, review and maintaining code

- Create component UI based on zeplin design.
- Build a feature.
- Review and maintain source code management.
- Lead a team in a weekly sharing session.
- communicate and Collaborate with other teams about best practice of software

Company : FindWork.io Sept 2016 – Apr 2017 (Singapore)

Position : Frontend Engineer

As a Frontend Engineer, i responsible to deliver design UI and it's functionality

• Create component based on zeplin design

• Writing readable, maintainable and reusable code.

• Build a feature and it's functionality using VueJs Framework

• Integrate backend API